hello and welcome to the Start table
大家好 欢迎来到起跑台
tutorial series I'm Brendan Rix with TJ
教程系列我是TJ的Brendan Rix
free and in this tutorial series we'll
免费的 在本系列教程中 我们将
learn how to manage and edit photos
了解如何管理和编辑照片
using dark table dark table is a great
使用暗桌暗桌是一个很棒的选择
professional program for working with
使用的专业计划
photography photographs if you're a
摄影摄影如果你是一名
photographer if you shoot with a DSLR
摄影师 如果你用单反拍摄
camera especially if you shoot in RAW or
相机 特别是当你拍摄未加工的或
even drone footage can be shot in RAW a
即使是无人机的镜头也可以在原始图像中拍摄
lot of smartphones can shoot in RAW
很多智能手机都可以直接拍摄
these days if you work with raw you're
如今 如果你和RAW一起工作 你就是
really gonna want to use dark table and
我真的很想用暗桌
it kind of does a lot of the same things
它做了很多相同的事情
that people often go to Photoshop or
人们经常去Photoshop或
before that does a much much better
在此之前 这要好得多
job than those programs do it gives you
它给你提供了比那些程序更好的工作
so much more control over your lighting
更好地控制您的照明
over the colors and over just really the
在颜色上 在真正的
look and feel if your photographs also
看起来感觉如果你的照片也
it has much much better management tools
它有更好的管理工具
and if you're ever working with multiple
如果您曾经处理过多个
pictures at once like trying to apply a
一次拍摄图片 就像尝试将
watermark on hundreds or thousands of
在成百上千个
pictures at once it's a great tool for
一次拍摄图片它是一个很好的工具
that if you're editing the metadata of
如果您正在编辑的元数据
the picture if you want to apply the
如果您要将
same thing over and over again like
一遍又一遍地做同样的事情 比如
rotate and zoom in and adjust colors but
旋转和放大以及调整颜色 但是
do it to like a dozen photos at once you
这样一来 你就可以同时喜欢一打的照片
don't need to go through and do it
不需要走过去和做这件事
individual you can just use this
个人 你可以只用这个
software to do all of that it's kind of
软件来完成所有这些工作 这有点像
similar to Adobe Lightroom in fact it's
与Adobe Lightroom类似 事实上它是
very similar to Adobe Lightroom and even
与Adobe Lightroom非常相似 甚至
a lot of professionals choose I've kind
很多专业人士都选择我喜欢的
of went away from Lightroom and they're
离开了Lightroom 他们
using darktable as their main workhorse
使用暗桌作为他们的主要主力
because it's just so professional and
因为它太专业了 而且
such an amazing piece of software so
如此令人惊叹的一款软件
it's not one of those free programs it's
它不是那种免费的程序 而是
just like a limited free and it's gonna
就像限量免费一样 它会
make you try to pay for more features in
让您尝试为更多功能付费
the future this is the real deal fully
未来 这才是真正的交易
professional it just happens to be open
专业人士只是碰巧是开放的
source and free so it's a project owned
源代码和免费 因此它是一个拥有的项目
by the community for the community this
由社区为社区这一点
is the software you need to be using if
是您在以下情况下需要使用的软件
you're a photographer of any kind or if
你是任何类型的摄影师或者如果
you work with photos a lot in this
在这部电影中 你经常使用照片
tutorial series we're going to learn how
系列教程 我们将学习如何
to use the interface we're gonna dive in
为了使用我们要潜入的界面
and learn how to use the different
并学习如何使用不同的
modules different color correcting and
模块不同的颜色校正和
filters and all of the cool things we
滤镜和我们所有很酷的东西
can do we'll learn how to do the batch
我们会学怎么做这批货的
editing how to import and export our
编辑如何导入和导出我们的
pictures and we'll just learn how
照片 我们只需学习如何
darktable functions what this is not
暗表的功能不是这样的
going to be is a deep way to learn how
将会是一种深入了解如何
to use the individual modules you could
要使用各个模块 您可以
spend years and you probably should
花上几年时间 你可能应该
spend years getting experience doing
花几年时间积累经验做
that that's something I haven't
那是我没有的东西
personally done and I just won't be able
亲自做了 我就是不能
to offer that so once we cover the
所以一旦我们谈到
basics in this series I hope you'll go
这一系列的基础知识 我希望你能去
out and find a lot of tutorials that are
并找到许多教程 这些教程是
there on the web and including on
在网络上 包括在
YouTube you can check out more
YouTube上您可以查看更多内容
specialized features of how to do a
如何做的专门功能
certain type of enhancement so that's
某种类型的增强 所以这是
kind of outside the scope of the series
有点超出了本系列的范围
just know that we're going to learn the
只要知道我们会学到
basics and we'll probably stop there one
基础知识 我们可能会到此为止
more thing before I close this video I
在我结束这段视频之前还有更多的事情要做
just want to talk about when to use
我只是想谈谈什么时候使用
darktable as opposed to Photoshop or
暗表 而不是Photoshop或
or credo or somebody's everyone's
或信条或某个人是每个人的
so photoshop's gonna be I mean darktable
所以Photoshop将会成为我的意思是暗桌
is going to be really good if you're
会很棒的如果你是
working with just photos so when people
只处理照片 所以当人们
do photo enhancements you're adjusting
做你正在调整的照片增强
lighting you're adjusting the size or
灯光你在调整大小还是
the crop or the frame of the image
图像的裁剪或边框
anything like that it's going to be
任何这样的事情都会是
great for improving skin tone or
对改善肤色或
bringing out certain colors or adjusting
调出某些颜色或进行调整
parts you know bringing shadows into the
你知道的将阴影带入
light or adjusting your lighting this is
照明或调整您的照明这是
what you want to do in darktable
你想在暗桌里做什么
if you want to do photoshop and maybe
如果你想做Photoshop 也许
like edit out blemishes on the skin you
比如把你皮肤上的瑕疵剪掉
can do some of that stuff in darktable
我可以在暗桌上做一些这样的事情
too but that's something more suited for
也是 但那是更适合的
and Photoshop or maybe compositing
和Photoshop 或者合成
multiple pictures on top of each other
多张图片叠加在一起
working with text or creating any kind
处理文本或创建任何类型的文本
of like brochures things like that
像宣传册之类的东西
you're going to want to use Photoshop
你会想要使用Photoshop
and for that and if you're creating
对于这一点 如果你正在创造
art from scratch like you have a drawing
从头开始的艺术 就像你有一幅画
pad or maybe you want to yeah draw it
Pad或者也许你想要画出来
with the mouse and draw circles and
用鼠标画圆圈 然后
create objects then you're going to want
创建对象 然后您将需要
to look into something more like crea
去研究更像是Crea的东西
even Inkscape and Photoshop and can
甚至Inkscape和Photoshop也可以
do some of that stuff too so let's just
也做一些那样的事情 所以让我们
sort of where this program Falls it's a
这个计划的失败之处在于它是一个
very good first step if you're working
如果你在工作 第一步走得很好
with an actual real photo if you're
一张真实的照片 如果你
working with digital art look into more
与数字艺术合作 了解更多
like crea
就像Crea一样
Photoshop for those kinds of things
这类东西的Photoshop
well I'm glad you found this tutorial
我很高兴你找到了这篇教程
series check out some way other videos
系列以某种方式签出其他视频
learning about open source software if
了解开放源码软件
you're not that familiar with it but
你不是很熟悉 但是
dive right in we're gonna learn how to
一头扎进水里 我们要学会如何
install darktable on your computer it
在您的计算机上安装Darktable它
runs on Windows Linux and Mac so we'll
在Windows、Linux和Mac上运行 因此我们将
get it installed and then we're gonna
把它安装好 然后我们就
dive right into learning how to use it
马上开始学习如何使用它
thanks for watching
感谢您的收看